net-temps.com 2009-06-16

# About Net-Temps

About Net-Temps

**Privacy Statement**  
Effective December, 2006 

[](http://www.truste.org/ivalidate.php?url=www.net-temps.com&sealid=101) Net-Temps is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build users. trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because Net-Temps wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, we have agreed to disclose our information practices and have our privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. By displaying the TRUSTe trustmark, Net-Temps ([www.net-temps.com](http://www.net-temps.com/)) has agreed to notify you of: 

  1. What personally identifiable information of yours or third party personally identifiable information that is collected from you through the website
  2. The organization collecting the information
  3. How the information is used
  4. With whom the information may be shared 
  5. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information
  6. The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under Net-Temps' control
  7. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact Net-Temps at (978) 251-7272 or by email at [ pr@net-temps.com](mailto:pr@net-temps.com). If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php>. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the website to resolve your concerns.

**Thawte SSL Web Server Certificate**  
The Net-Temps server is secured through the Thawte SSL (secure sockets layer) Web Server Certificate which ensures that any information sent to the Net-Temps server is encrypted, making it virtually impossible to intercept or steal online communications during transmittal. Personal information and credit card details cannot be viewed by outside parties and once such information has been submitted, the data cannot be tampered with while it is being transmitted.

**Privacy Policy**  
This privacy statement covers the site [www.net-temps.com](http://www.net-temps.com/) and [www.nettemps.com](http://www.nettemps.com/)

We understand the power that the Internet holds for changing your life and making things easier for you. These benefits are at risk if people are concerned about their personal privacy. We are committed to providing you with an Internet experience that respects and protects your personal privacy choices and concerns.

In general, we gather information about all of our users collectively. We only use such information anonymously and in the aggregate. This information helps us determine what is most beneficial for our users, and how we can continually create a better overall experience for you. We may share this information with our partners, but only in the aggregate, so that they too may understand how Net-Temps' visitors use our site, so they may create a better overall experience for you, as well.

**Email Links**  
Net-Temps provides email address links located on the Contact Us page so that you may email us directly with any questions or comments you may have. Net-Temps reads all messages received and makes efforts to respond promptly. In addition to replying to your comment or inquiry, we may also file your email for future reference regarding improvements to our website or discard the information. Your personal information is not shared to third parties without your express permission.

**Information Collection and Use**  
Net-Temps is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. Net-Temps collects information from our users at several different points on our website.

**Membership Information**  
Companies wishing to sign up for Net-Temps' service are asked to provide certain data including full name, complete mailing address, phone number and email address. Members can expect to receive periodic email communications including resume search agent results, a hot list of candidates, updates regarding their service and the weekly newsletter. If members do not wish to receive resume search agents results or a daily hotlist, they may remove the agents from their desktop and disable the daily hotlist. An unsubscribe is provided at the bottom of each recruiter newsletter if they wish to opt-out. 

Members have the ability to update/change their company information and user information including contact name, email address, password and phone number. Each account has a designated administrator who has the ability to change any of this information in their password-protected recruiting center. 

Net-Temps membership is a paid service and available on a month-to month basis or 6 or 12-month contract basis. Membership may be cancelled with 30 days prior notice to the contract renewal date. 

**Single Job Posting**  
If a company wishes to post a single job on Net-Temps, the name, company name, complete mailing address and email address are required. In addition credit card and expiration information is also required. This information is then processed by VeriSign, Inc., a third party service provider. 

**Personal Resume Bank**  
The Personal Resume Bank allows Net-Temps Recruiters to create a private database of resumes from the Recruiters Desktop. Resumes entered into the Personal Resume Bank from the Net-Temps resume banks are accessible to anyone with an active Net-Temps subscription account. Resumes entered into the Personal Resume Bank from a source other than the Net-Temps resume banks are accessible to only that recruiter; the Recruiters Desktop is password protected. If a recruiter elects to cancel their account, they may email all the resumes in their Personal Resume Bank to any email address they choose and/or print the resumes.

**Forums**  
Net-Temps provides job seeker career forums for each of its career channels. These areas are not restricted and are accessible by anyone visiting the website and Net-Temps personnel. The information provided in the forum is publicly displayed and users should use caution when posting online. If you use the career forums on this site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. Net-Temps reserves the right to remove any messages in the forums and terminate the accounts of visitors who use these services in a manner inconsistent with the Net-Temps Terms of Use. 

**Personal Information**  
Net-Temps' resume functionality requires/requests users to give us contact information (such as their email address) and personal information (such as their work histories and academic achievements). The user's contact and personal information is used to contact the visitor when necessary, but is primarily used in the construction of the user's resume and Candidate Profile.

Demographic data that are collected at our site are not required, and are shared with clients only on an aggregate basis, primarily to aid employers with their own EEO compliance and affirmative action policies. We do not disclose information about your individual visits to Net-Temps, or personal information that you provide, such as your name, address, email address, telephone number, credit card number, personal references, etc., to any outside parties, except when we believe the law requires it. But, we may record and share aggregated information with our partners.

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site or share content, we will ask you for your friend.s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site or read the content. Net-Temps stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. 

Your friend may contact us at service@net-temps.com to request that we remove this information from our database. 

Net-Temps offers the ability to send newsletter and article content found on the website to a friend via email. Net-Temps requires both the senders' and recipients' email addresses in order for the newsletter/article be sent. This information is stored on Net-Temps but is not shared or sold to third parties.

Visitors may also sign up for our free jobseeker or recruiter weekly newsletters. The only information required is an email address. This information will not be shared with our partners and subscribers may opt-out at any time by following the remove procedures provided in each newsletter.

We post customer and jobseeker testimonials on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information such as the customer's or jobseeker.s name. We do obtain their consent prior posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. 

**Legal Disclaimer**  
We may disclose personal information when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with a legal process serviced on our website.

**Resume Posting**  
When you post your resume, you have the option of suppressing your contact information. You also have the ability of making the resume active or non-active. An active resume will be accessible to all employers and recruiters who pay for access to our resume database product. We use our best efforts to grant access to this database only to paying employers, recruiters, hiring managers, headhunters, and human resource professionals, but cannot guarantee that other parties will not, without our consent, gain access to this database. You may remove your resume from our searchable database by deleting the resume or by making it inactive. However, employers and recruiters who have paid for access to the database, and other parties who have otherwise gained access to the database, may have retained a copy of your resume in their own files or databases. We are not responsible for the retention, use, or privacy of resumes in these instances, or for the use or privacy of resumes by any of such parties while resumes are in the database.

**Privacy Protection Tips**  
Net-Temps recommends that you follow these guidelines when applying to a job or posting a resume online: 

  * Never include your social security number.

  * Never disclose personally identifying information such as marital status or physical descriptions like eye color or weight when it does not relate to the job.

  * Do not put down any financial information including bank accounts or credit cards.

  * Use caution when communicating with employers outside of the country.

**Change/Modify Job Seeker Profile and Resume Information**  
This site gives job seeker users options for changing and modifying information previously provided. Login to your Job Seekers Desktop at <http://my.net-temps.com/login.html> and select 'My Profile' to modify account information. To edit specific resume information, select 'Access Resumes'.

**Delete/Opt-Out**  
The majority of our email communications will have instructions on how to unsubscribe so that you will not receive any future emails from us if you so choose. For example, users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter may unsubscribe by sending an email to [infocus@net-temps.com](mailto:infocus@net-temps.com) or [crossroads@net-temps.com](mailto:crossroads@net-temps.com) with the word 'REMOVE' in the Subject line. Job search agents results may also be removed by deleting them from the Job Search Assistant.

**Links**  
Net-Temps contains links to other websites. These sites have their own policies and practices with respect to online privacy, and Net-Temps cannot be responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these websites. In addition, in certain instances a Net-Temps advertiser may ask you for personal information. Net-Temps cannot be responsible for the privacy practices of its advertisers.

 **Co-Branded Partners**  
Partners via co-branded websites provide many of Net-Temps' resume and interview services. Some of these co-branded websites require users to provide personal information including full name and email address in order to proceed in order to proceed in the purchase process of the service. Not all of the co-branded websites are covered by the Net-Temps Privacy Policy and users should read the partners' privacy statements carefully before proceeding. 

**Troubleshooting**  
We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our website. An Internet protocol (I.P.) address is a set of numbers that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you log on to your Internet service provider or through your company's local area network (LAN) or wide area network (WAN). IP addresses are tied to personally identifiable information to enable our web-based service. 

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer tied to information about the user. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is one stored as a file on your computer, and it remains there when you close Internet Explorer. The cookie can be read by the Web site that created it when you visit that site again. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions. You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. Each browser is different so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences. 

We do link the information we store in cookies to personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. By setting a cookie on our site, users do not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. This information is stored and used to create a custom account for the user and make available information tailored to their requests (such as career-specific information like hot jobs, job search agents and news). If users reject the cookie, they may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of our site. For example, the user will not be able to have career-specific information automatically available upon sign in (hot jobs, search agents and news). 

Some of our business partners and advertisers use cookies on our site. However, we have no access to or control over these cookies once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising. 

**Surveys & Contests**  
From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contest is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and email address), and demographic information (such as zip code). Contact information will be used to notify winners and award prizes. In addition, contest winners' names and address (city and state) are posted on the website. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. All personal information collected is done so by Net-Temps and is not shared or sold to third parties. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site.

**Children**  
We do not specifically collect information about children. We believe that children should get their parents' consent before giving out personal information. If you are concerned about your child's use of Net-Temps, we encourage you to use web filtering technology to supervise your child's access to the site. We also encourage you to participate in your child's experience with Net-Temps. With a little guidance, the site can prove very useful in finding a part-time or summer job for your child, as well as providing them with excellent career counseling information.

**Security**  
We operate secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection. We have security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of your user data under our control. 

Only certain employees have access to the information you provide us. For example, we impose strict rules on our employees who have access either to the databases that store user information or to the servers that host our services. While we cannot guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration to data will not occur, we try to prevent such unfortunate occurrences.

**Notification of Changes**  
This policy may be revised over time as new features are added to the website. We will post those changes so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and whether we will disclose it to anyone. Please check this site for information about revisions to our privacy policy. 

We will notify you directly if there is a material change in our privacy practices. We will take commercially reasonable measures to obtain written or active email consent from the user if Net-Temps is going to be using the information collected from the user in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection. We will also post the changes in our privacy statement 30 days prior to a change. 

**Contact Information**  
If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at: 

Phone: 800-307-0062  
Fax: 978-251-7250  
Email: [pr@net-temps.com](mailto:pr@net-temps.com)  
Website: <http://www.net-temps.com/about/contact.htm>  

55 Middlesex Street  
Suite 220  
North Chelmsford, MA 01863
